ANTHONY GOONERATNE

B.SC. HONS, PMP



anthony.dswg@gmail.com



613-204-8523



/anthony-gooneratne-pmp



Ottawa

SKILLS

Project Management

Agile, Scrum, Waterfall Methods

Stakeholder Relations

Project Estimation and Bidding

Contract Management

Conflict Management

Research and Analysis

Technical

Solution Testing &

Implementation

MS Project / Office Suite /

VISIO/ Windows Desktop/

Server

SQL / IOS/ IBM AS 400

Google Sheets

WAN/LAN

Customer Service

Customer Relations

Management

Conflict Mediation

Executive Management Support

Technical Support

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Focused Project Manager with over 13 years of experience in managing, implementing, and delivering IT Projects. Passionate in utilizing the skills, education, and experience gained to be an effective contributor to the company's business needs by achieving organizational and regulatory expectations.

SUMMARY OF ROLES

- Worked as the Project Manager for IT system and infrastructure implementation
 projects for multiple leading banks in Sri Lanka for over ten years. Delivered projects
 in the domains of: System integration, CRM, Business Intelligence (BI), Core
 banking system migration, Infrastructure implementation, Surveillance system,
 PABX and Process automation.
- Led multiple technology and data migrations for a core banking system migration project (Fiserv) which was completed in a record time frame in the banking industry of Sri Lanka.
- Planned and delivered a range of business-critical IT systems and infrastructure implementation projects simultaneously from conception to completion within established deadlines and budgets.

WORK HISTORY

TD BANK - CUSTOMER SERVICE RESOLUTIONS ANALYST

Ottawa, ON • 09/2021 - Current

- Analyzing issues raised by clients pertaining to business products and provides solutions and recommendations.
- Working in a team setting, by providing support and guidance.
- Ensuring all resolutions provided comply with Bank of Canada regulatory requirements.

COSTCO CANADA – E-COMMERCE AGENT

Ottawa, ON • 06/2020 - 08/2021

AMANA BANK – IT PROJECT MANAGER / IT SYSTEM AND INFRASTRUCTURE Colombo, Sri Lanka • 06/2011 - 11/2019

- Coordinated project resources across technical, administrative, business teams, and third-party vendors.
- Maintained a high success rate of effective implementation of financial system and infrastructure projects across the bank's divisions.
- Closely worked with Consultants and Program Leaders to identify the business needs which were analyzed to determine the technical requirements of the project scopes.
- Created request for proposals (RFP), business requirement documentation in adherence to PMI standards.

EDUCATION

National University of Ireland -BSc. Hons. Degree: Management Information Systems (MIS)

National Institution of Business Management – *Diploma in Computer System Design*

Carleton University
Full-Stack WEB Developer Boot
Camp (Will be complete in Feb
2024)

CERTIFICATION

Project Management Institute (PMI) - Project Management Professional (PMP)

BUREAU VERITAS - Lead Auditor (Information Security Management Systems)

AFFILIATIONS

Member of PMI

Member of PMI OVOC Ottawa

Mentee for PMI OVOC 2020 Mentorship Forum

- Defined best practices by moving between agile and waterfall approaches depending on project specifics and owners' requirements.
- Monitored project progress, identified risks, and took corrective action as needed.
- Conducted user acceptance testing (UAT) for continual refinement of system processes.
- Effectively bridged the knowledge gap between stakeholders and internal teams that significantly helped to minimize scope creep and issue escalations.
- Communicated progress using reports, graphs, presentations, and dashboards to the management team, project steering committee, consultants, and clients on a regular basis.

SDB BANK - SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST

Colombo, Sri Lanka • 03/2009 - 06/2011

- Managed implementation, support, and troubleshooting of core banking system and other integrated applications of the bank.
- Researched and identified business improvements and determined appropriate systems required for process improvements. Created and managed implementations of process automation. Reduced processing time by 60% for key processing workflows.
- Created and maintained standard operating procedures governing system functions and features.
- Trained business personnel in use of systems.
- Led periodical Business Continuity Process and Disaster Recovery drills.

SDB BANK - APPLICATION AND INFRASTRUCTURE SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Colombo, Sri Lanka • 01/2007 - 03/2009

- Oversaw implementation, support, and troubleshooting of core banking systems other banking application.
- Monitors and controls the operation of the mainframe hardware and software.
- Ran EOD | EOM and EOY backups on all banking applications and databases at the primary data center as well as disaster recovery site
- Provide end-user support and assistance on VPN | Antivirus etc
- Configure CISCO call manger and provide end use support

•

DESJARDINS, SDB BANK SRI LANKA - SOLUTIONS SPECIALIST

Colombo, Sri Lanka • 06/2006 - 03/2008

- Designed the technical architecture for the central recovery database (CRDB) platform.
- Managed project procurement.
- Coordinated and implemented the CRDB application and its infrastructures (e.g., development of the application, implement application hosting servers, data communication devices and security firewall).
- Conducted user training and connected over 100 micro financing institutions to the CRDB system.